# Ei Pa Pa Pe-Than

eipa [at] cmu [dot] edu | <a href="https://eipapa.github.io/">https://eipapa.github.io/</a> | <a href="Google Scholar">Google Scholar</a> | <a href="Research Gate">Research Gate</a> | <a href="@eipa01">@eipa01</a> | <a href="GitHub">GitHub</a>

## **Research Interests and Approach**

My research interests span computer-supported cooperative work (CSCW), science and technologies studies (STS), and critical human-computer interaction (HCI), and especially how to develop, maintain, and evolve a distributed decentralized software system that builds on a novel and sophisticated coordination architecture that addresses reinterpretability, resilience, and scalability.

I use case study research approach to address complex socio-technical questions, which includes ethnography (interviews and non-participant observations), archival analysis, quantitative collection of log and trace data with Python, SQL, and R, and a combination of all of these methods (mixed-methods) as relevant and appropriate.

### **Education**

Carnegie Mellon U	University Pittsburgh, PA, USA
2017–present	Postdoctoral Researcher Advisor: James Herbsleb, Institute for Software Research, School of Computer Science Topic: Large-scale coordination in time-bounded events (hackathons, datathons, etc.) for science, innovation, learning, and community building, and open-text projects on GitHub
Nanyang Technol	ogical University Singapore, Singapore
2010–2016	Doctor of Philosophy in Information Systems  Advisor: Dion Hoe-Lian Goh and Chei Sian Lee, Wee Kim Wee School of Communication and Information  Thesis: Investigating user-centered human computation games: The role of perceived enjoyment and its antecedents
2008–2009	Master of Science in Information Systems
University of Con	nputer Studies
2001–2005	Bachelor of Science (Hons.) in Computer Science

# **Employment**

Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh, PA, USA				
2017–present	Postdoctoral Researcher Advisor: James Herbsleb, Institute for Software Research, School of Computer Science Topic: Coordination in time-bounded events (hackathons, datathons, etc.) for science, innovation, learning, and community building, and collaborative writing on GitHub			
Nanyang Technological University				
2015–2016	Research Associate and Part-time Lecturer			
NCS	Application Consultant (Software Developer)			
2007 2010	Application Consultant (Software Developer)			
University of Computer Studies				
2005–2007	Tutor			

### **Publications**

#### **Referred Journal Publications**

- 1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Nolte, A., Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S., and Herbsleb, J.D. "Corporate Hackathons, How and Why? A Multiple Case Study of Motivation, Project Proposal and Selection, Goal Setting, Coordination, and Project Continuation." [Revisions submitted to Human-Computer Interaction Journal]
- 2. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Dabbish, L., and Herbsleb, J.D. "Collaborative Writing at Scale: Investigation of Pull-Based Model on GitHub." [Under the review of CSCW 2020]
- 3. Nolte, A., **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "You Hacked and Now What?: Exploring Outcomes of a Corporate Hackathon." In Proceedings of the ACM on Human Computer Interaction, 2 (CSCW'18), Article 129, 23 pages. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3274398">https://doi.org/10.1145/3274398</a>
- 4. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Nolte, A., Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "Designing Corporate Hackathons with a Purpose." IEEE Software, 36 (1), 15-22. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.23863">https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.23863</a>

#### **Referred Conference Publications**

 Pe-Than, E.P.P. and Herbsleb, J.D. (2019). "Understanding Hackathons for Science: Collaboration, Affordances, and Outcomes." In Taylor N., Christian-Lamb C., Martin M., Nardi B. (eds) Information in Contemporary Society, iConference'19. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 11420 (iConference'19), pp. 27-37. Springer, Cham. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-15742-5">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-15742-5</a> 3

#### **Referred Short Publications**

1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Dabbish, L., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "Collaborative Writing on GitHub: A Case Study of a Book Project." In Companion of the 2018 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW'18), pp. 305-308. https://doi.org/10.1145/3272973.3274083

#### **Referred Workshop Publications**

Pe-Than, E.P.P., Herbsleb, J.D., Nolte, A., Gerber, E., Fiore-Gartland, B., Chapman, B., Moser, A., and Wilkins-Diehr, N. (2018). "The 2nd Workshop on Hacking and Making at Time-Bounded Events: Current Trends and Next Steps in Research and Event Design." In Extended Abstracts of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI EA'18), paper W35, 8 pages. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3170427.3170615">https://doi.org/10.1145/3170427.3170615</a>

#### **Technical Reports**

1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, and Nolte, A. (2018). "The 2nd Workshop on Hacking and Making at Time-Bounded Events." Technical Report CMU-ISR-18-109, Carnegie Mellon University. http://eipapa.github.io/files/ISR-techreport-2018.pdf

#### **Posters**

- 1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Dabbish, L., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2019). "Collaborative Writing at Scale: A Case Study of Two Open-Text Projects Done on GitHub." Paper presented at The Future of Work, Human Computer Interaction Consortium (HCIC'19). <a href="http://eipapa.github.io/files/HCIC-poster-2019.pdf">http://eipapa.github.io/files/HCIC-poster-2019.pdf</a>
- 2. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Dabbish, L., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2019). "Collaborative Writing at Scale: A Case Study of Two Open-Text Projects Done on GitHub." Poster presented at the 7th ACM Conference on Collective Intelligence 2019 (CI'19). <a href="https://ci.acm.org/2019/assets/proceedings/CI\_2019\_paper\_65.pdf">https://ci.acm.org/2019/assets/proceedings/CI\_2019\_paper\_65.pdf</a> <a href="https://eipapa.github.io/files/CI-poster-2019.pdf">https://eipapa.github.io/files/CI-poster-2019.pdf</a>
- 3. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Momcheva, I., Tolleud, E., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2019). "Hackathons for Science, How and Why?" Poster presented at the 233rd Meeting of the American

- 4. Powell, J., Hayden, L., Nolte, A., Herbsleb, J.D., **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Wong, M., Kalyanam, R., Ellet, K., Pamidighantam, S., Traxler, K., and Cannon, A. (2018). "An Analysis of the PEARC 2018 Science Gateways Community Institute Hackathon: Lessons Learned." Poster presented at Gateways 2018 organized by the Science Gateways Community Institute (SGCI). https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.7070309.v2
- 5. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Nolte, A., Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S. and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "An Empirical Study of Team Familiarity, Goal Setting, and Process in Time-Bounded Events." Poster presented at the 13th Annual Interdisciplinary Network for Group Research Conference (INGRoup'18).

### **Selected Publications from Doctoral Research Projects**

- 1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D.H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2017). "Does it matter how you play? The effects of collaboration and competition among players of human computation games." Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology (JASIST), 68 (8), 1823-1835. https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.23863
- 2. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D.H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2015). "A typology of human computation games: An analysis and a review of current games." Behaviour and Information Technology, 34 (8), 809-824. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/0144929X.2013.862304">https://doi.org/10.1080/0144929X.2013.862304</a>
- 3. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D.H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2014). "Making work fun: Investigating antecedents of perceived enjoyment in human computation games for information sharing." Computers in Human Behavior, 39 (2014), 88-99. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chb.2014.06.023

### **Teaching**

### Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Instructor			
CI6221	Information Visualization (cross-listed, graduate)		
CI6228	Managing Information Systems (graduate)	Jan 2016	
IN9008	Digital Social Games for Organizations (undergraduate)	Jan 2015	
Teaching Assistan	t		
Teaching Assistan			
IN9006	Social Computing and Applications (graduate)	Jan 2014	
CS2008	Fundamentals of Research (undergraduate)	Aug 2013	
CI6208	Research Methods and Data Analysis for Information	Jan 2013	
	Professionals (graduate)		
CI6222	Mobile & Ubiquitous Applications (graduate)	Aug 2012	

### **University of Computer Studies, Yangon**

**Tutor** Fundamentals of Data Structures (undergraduate) 2006-2007

Operating Systems (undergraduate) 2006-2007

### **Professional Services**

Reviewing	
2020	ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems iConference
2019	ACM CSCW: ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems iConference
2018	ACM CHI: ACM Conference on Computer-Human Interaction ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems iConference
2017	ACM CHI: ACM Conference on Computer-Human Interaction Journal of Information Science Theory and Practice
2016	Cyberpsychology, Behavior, and Social Networking Aslib Journal of Information Management
2015	ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems
Organizing	
2019	World of Code (WoC) Hackathon, Carnegie Mellon University
2018	Science Gateways Hackathon by the Science Gateways Community Institute (SGCI), collocated with PEARC18 Conference, Wyndham Grand Pittsburgh
2018	The 2nd Workshop on Hacking and Making at Time-Bounded Events: Current Trends and Next Steps in Research and Event Design, ACM CHI'18 conference, Montreal, Canada
Volunteering	

2016 The 66th	Annual Conference	of the International	Communication	Association
---------------	-------------------	----------------------	---------------	-------------

(ICA)

Graduate Admission Exercise, Wee Kim Wee School of Communication and 2011-2013

Information

2011 International Conference on Social Informatics (SocInfo2011)

# **Research Funding**

NTU Doctoral Research scholarship

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Duration: August 2010-August 2014

Amount: S\$ 111,600

3K Grant for Research Student

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Duration: 2011–2014 Amount: S\$ 2,800

Conference Travel Grant

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Year: 2016

Amount: S\$ 1,000

### **Professional Associations**

ACM Association for Computing Machinery

ACM SIGCHI Special Interest Group on Computer–Human Interaction

ACM SIGSOFT Special Interest Group on Software Engineering
ASIS&T Association for Information Science & Technology